Ushindi Bienvenu

Full-Stack Web Developer with a 5-year track record in building effective and optimized web solutions across diverse industries, including fintech, logistics, and education. I thrive on exploring new technologies and embarking on exciting side project

Email: ushindi bienvenu Linkedin: usbbush

Github: <u>bienvenuushindi</u>
Blog: <u>Ushindi Medium Blog</u>

EXPERIENCE

EvoluData, Remote — Software Engineer

July 2024 - PRESENT

Ensured a seamless user experience by diligently identifying and resolving bugs, developed and integrated new features to significantly expand platform functionality and user base, and authored comprehensive technical documentation to empower users and developers.

JUUBIX, Remote — Software Engineer

July 2023 - July 2024

Designed and implemented a matching algorithm for a custom web platform, collaborated with UX/UI designers to transform wireframes into fully functional software solutions ensuring a seamless user experience, and fostered a culture of accountability through regular team syncs to meet development milestones

MICROVERSE, Remote — Code Reviewer

Oct 2022 - January 2024

Successfully conducted code and UI reviews for over 600 students, providing feedback and guidance to enhance their development skills, collaborated with the technical team to develop and implement new coding standards and best practices, and researched and integrated new technologies to improve the company's code review process.

SKILLS

JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, Ruby, Rails, Laravel, Nestjs, React, NodeJs, MongoDB, MySQL, Postgresql

LANGUAGES

English, French

FREELANCE, Remote / On Site — Full-stack Developer

January 2019 – April 2022

Developed a secure shop management system for a client to enhance operational efficiency, built a cross-cultural marketplace for Congo and Uganda to facilitate seamless trade, implemented comprehensive website design and optimization techniques to improve online presence and reduce page load times by 30%, and collaborated with UX/UI designers to transform wireframes into functional software solutions, utilizing SEO best practices to improve search engine rankings

EDUCATION

International University of East Africa - Computer science

Bachelor's degree

January 2015 - November 2018

Designed and implemented an emergency tracking and response system.

PROJECTS

TuJunga - Online Commerce

A comprehensive solution designed to streamline and simplify the process of managing product requisitions for a small boutique. The primary goal is to alleviate the challenges faced by the person in charge of purchasing supplies by digitizing and automating various tasks associated with the traditional paper-based requisition process.

Sharingan - Knowledge Based System

knowledge based system built to help code reviewers quickly search for specific code review guidelines and generate a ready to use comment for each requirement that is not followed.

For more projects you can visit my website.